

Website: thomjamesallen.com
GitHub: github.com/tjallen
Email: thomwork@gmail.com

Mobile: 07747 229 007

Summary

I'm a front-end web developer passionate about building **effective**, **user-friendly web experiences**. I've spent the majority of recent years working on the front-end of web apps, typically using **React**, but also have full stack experience and am always keen to expand my skill set to other areas.

History

Zzish, Front-end Developer

Apr 2018 - Mar 2020

Spent two years working as part of the tech team at <u>Zzish</u>, an education technology startup who focus on improving the education experience for teachers and students, primarily via their award-winning teaching platform and assessment tool, <u>Quizalize</u>.

- Maintained and implemented new features into existing web apps (**Quizalize**, formative assessment tool & **ZzishHub** for student results & differentiated learning)
- Created greenfield web apps like <u>Zzish Insights</u>, making design decisions on front-end architecture
- Migrated stack to more modern or preferred tech (Flow to TypeScript, Relay Classic to Modern to Apollo, React class components to Hooks, PostCSS to Styled Components)
- Focused on usability and performance, working closely with designers, UX and PMs
- Assisted with back-end tickets as required to ease team workload
- Onboarded and mentored junior devs; wrote documentation and collaborated on forming team best practices

Tech: React, Relay / Apollo, GraphQL, JavaScript ES6 + TypeScript / Flow, Node + Express, MongoDB, Webpack, Python

Antidote, freelance Front-end Developer

Jan 2018

Created HTML5 banner ads for client Royal Ascot

ASOS, contract Front-end Developer

May 2017

Contracted at **ASOS**' head office in Camden, building microsites for their brand partnerships with clients **PayPal** and **Hostelworld**. Used Gulp scripts to build from Pug templates into an array of static files, targeting various devices & languages.

Tech: HTML5, SASS, Gulp, Pug

Dunnhumby, contract Front-end Developer & QA

Jan 2017

Spent 4 weeks in-house at **Dunnhumby** HQ in Hammersmith, providing QA for **Tesco Groceries**' XML-based banner ads along with workflow consultancy. Prototyped approvals-oriented web app with Knockout.js and responsive ad components with React.

Tech: HTML5/XML, CSS, Knockout.js, React

StirPR, contract Front-end Developer

Dec 2016

Developed responsive HTML emails for client Felix from PSDs.

Tech: HTML5, SASS, Foundation

Antidote, freelance Front-end Developer

May 2016

Worked in-house at **Antidote's** Fitzrovia offices as part of a two developer team, creating banner ads for client **Travel Republic's** summer campaign for a wide variety of destinations and formats. Created a simple jQuery-based ad viewer to help the agency team quickly review changes & assist with deadlines.

Tech: HTML5, SASS, JavaScript + jQuery, Greensock.js

Antidote, freelance Front-end Developer

Jan 2016

More work at **Antidote**, for clients **Libratone**, creating a custom player module for YouTube 360° videos to be used on a landing page, working to a strict deadline. Refactored first-draft JS into a revealing module pattern and added BEM and 7-1 code conventions. Created documentation for handover.

Tech: HTML5, SASS, JavaScript + jQuery, YouTube API

Phosphor Art, part-time developer

2014 - 2015

Built responsive promos and landing pages alongside maintaining their existing site. Created HTML email campaigns & email builder, newsletter signup forms etc. Created a responsive online store page prototype using ExpressionEngine.

Tech: WordPress, ExpressionEngine, PayPal API, HTML5, SASS, JavaScript, jQuery

Stuff & Sense, part-time developer & consultant

2013 - 2014

Designed & built the Stuff & Sense company site with a responsive front-end and an ExpressionEngine-based back-end. Provided consultancy services to various clients.

Tech: ExpressionEngine, WordPress, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, ProcessWire

Other work

Freelance web developer

2009 - present

Designed, built and managed sites, landing pages and apps for various small business clients.

Tech: HTML5, CSS + SASS, JavaScript + jQuery, WordPress, React, PHP (EE/Grav), Gulp, Webpack

Open source developer

2016 – 2018 primarily

- Created open-source apps and contributed to others' repositories.
- Created <u>react-simple-range</u>, an open-source React slider component released as an NPM package. Uses semantic-release & Travis CI for automated releases & package publishing when updates are committed to master. Collaborated with open-source contributors to add features & fix bugs. Getting pretty old and dusty but has 27k downloads as of 2020 so evidently someone is using it!
- <u>countdown-app</u>: A simple React countdown timer, built both a webapp and an Electron-based desktop version.

Tech: JavaScript, React, Vue, Redux, MobX, Flux, Electron, Styled Components, Hexo, Gatsby, Jekyll, Chrome web API, Jest, Enzyme, Mocha, Cosmos, Storybook, Webpack, Travis Cl

Education & etc

Self-taught developer. 10 GCSEs A* – C, The Ravensbourne School. References available on request